Guide to the Skinner Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Skinner family papers
1802-1849
MS 1211
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
5.33
(5 boxes)
The papers consist of correspondence and financial records of John Skinner concerning the Rimmon Falls Turnpike Company and his medical practice in East Hartford, Connecticut. Also included are notes, made by Roger Sherman Skinner, of lectures by James Gould at the Litchfield Law School.
Skinner family
Existence and Location of Copies
Notes made by Roger Sherman Skinner of lectures by James Gould at the Litchfield Law School, 1815-1816 are also available on microfilm (1 reel, 35mm.) from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM246.
Biographical / Historical
John Skinner (1765-1850): physician; sheriff of New Haven County in 1809; treasurer of Rimmon Falls Turnpike Co. Roger Sherman Skinner (1795-1838): lawyer; practiced in New Haven 1816-1828; clerk of city and county courts around 1820; 1828 moved to New York City.
Roger Sherman Skinner, the eldest and only surviving child of Dr. John Skinner, of East Hartford, Connecticut, and grandson of John and Sarah (Kennedy) Skinner, of East Windsor, was born in East Hartford on January 19, 1795. His mother was Chloe, daughter of the Hon. Roger and Elizabeth (Hartwell) Sherman, of New Haven. The family settled in New Haven about 1799, and the son was prepared for College by Elizur Goodrich, Junior (Williams Coll. 1806) at the Hopkins Grammar School.
On graduation he entered the Yale Medical School, but soon transferred himself to Litchfield Law School and in March 1816, was admitted to the bar.
He settled in New Haven, and was married on September 27, 1817, to Mary Lockwood, daughter of Lockwood and Mehitable (Wheeler) DeForest, of New York.
He was for several years, about 1820, Clerk of the City and County Courts.
About 1828 he removed to New York City.
He died while temporarily in Peru, Lasalle County, Illinois, on December 6, 1838, in his 44th year.
His children were three sons and three daughters, all of whom survived him. The second daughter married the Rev. Samuel D. Marsh (Yale 1844), and is now the widow of the Rev. Professor Samuel Harris, of the Yale Divinity School, while the youngest daughter is the wife of President Timothy Dwight (Yale 1849).
His widow died at President Dwight's house in New Haven, on June 17, 1889, aged 92 years.
Taken from F.B. Dexter, Yale Biographies and Annals, Vol. VI, 603-604.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence and financial records of John Skinner concerning the Rimmon Falls Turnpike Company and his medical practice in East Hartford, Connecticut. Also included are notes, made by Roger Sherman Skinner, of lectures by James Gould at the Litchfield Law School.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Families; Law -- Study and teaching; Medicine -- Practice; East Hartford (Conn.); Account books; Lawyers; Physicians; Gould, James, 1770-1838; Skinner, John, 1765-1850; Skinner, Roger Sherman; Skinner family; Litchfield Law School; Rimmon Falls Turnpike Company
- Inventory
  - John Skinner (1765-1850)
    - Correspondence and legal papers, 1819, 1830, 1831, 1846 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bills and receipts, 1827-1836 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Receipts for renewal of policy with Hartford Fire Insurance Company, 1827-1847 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Ledger, 1802-1809 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Day book and ledger, 1802-1849 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Roger Sherman Skinner (1795-1838)
    - Notes on James Gould's lectures, 1815 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Notes on James Gould's lectures, 1816 (Box 5, Folder 7)